persimmonhomes.com 2011-12-21

# Privacy Policy

## 1 Introduction

  * **1.1** The website under the domain name http://www.persimmon.com/ (the Site) is operated by Persimmon plc. We are responsible for the processing of your personal data and we are the data controller for all such information. 
  * **1.2** We have developed this Privacy Policy so that you may feel confident about the privacy and security of your personal information. This Privacy Policy (together with the terms of use of the Site and any other documents referred to on it) sets out the basis on which any personal data we collect from you, or that you provide to us, will be processed by us, the purpose of our collection of it and how we protect the information.

## 2 Data Protection

  * **2.1** As data controller, we take all necessary steps to comply with the Data Protection Act 1998 (as amended, restated or re-enacted from time to time) and its relevant subordinate legislation when handling any personal information.
  * **2.2** When you supply any personal information to us we will meet our legal obligations to you in the way that we deal with that information.
  * **2.3** In accordance with the Data Protection Act 1998 we are required to collect the information fairly and to let you know how we will use it (see Clause 3) and whether we will pass the information on to anyone else (see Clause 4).
  * **2.4** We will comply with the Principles set out in the Data Protection Act 1998.
  * **2.5** We will take reasonable precautions to safeguard your personal data against loss and unauthorised disclosure or access (see Clause 6).
  * **2.6** A reference to a statute, statutory provision or subordinate legislation is a reference to it as it is in force from time to time, taking account of any amendment to or re-enactment of it. 

## 3 Use of Personal Information

  * **3.1** We may collect and process the following personal information about you: 
    * **3.1.1** name;
    * **3.1.2** address; 
    * **3.1.3** contact telephone number;
    * **3.1.4** mobile telephone number;
    * **3.1.5** contact e-mail address;
    * **3.1.6** when you register and log in;
    * **3.1.7** the developments and properties that you view on the Site or save; 
    * **3.1.8** when you respond to requests to submit personal information about yourself; and
    * **3.1.9** if you contact us, we may keep a record of that correspondence.
  * **3.2** We may also keep a record of those parts of the Site that you use most often to enable us to monitor, support, improve and develop our service and to know which parts are of the most interest to you.
  * **3.3** We will use the personal information supplied by you to: 
    * **3.3.1** administer your membership account;
    * **3.3.2** deliver marketing information to you from us, where you have consented to be contacted for such purposes;
    * **3.3.3** provide you with updates on developments, where you have consented to be contacted for such purposes;
    * **3.3.4** help you keep track of developments and properties that you have saved, where you have consented to be contacted for such purposes;
    * **3.3.5** ensure that content from the Site is presented in the most effective manner for you and for your computer;
    * **3.3.6** contact you for your views on our services and events and notify you occasionally about important changes or developments to the Site or our services.
  * **3.4** By using the Site you consent to our collection and use of this information. 
  * **3.5** The information you supply to us will be held on our computers hosted by fuse8.
  * **3.6** You can at any time send an email to datachanges@persimmonhomes.com if you decide that you no longer wish to receive information provided to you under Clauses 3.3.2, 3.3.3 and 3.3.4.

## 4 Disclosure of Personal Information

  * **4.1** We take all reasonable care to prevent any unauthorised access to your personal data.
  * **4.2** We may disclose your personal information to any member of our group, which means our subsidiaries, our ultimate holding company and its subsidiaries, as defined in section 736 of the UK Companies Act 1985.
  * **4.3** We will only supply your personally identifiable information to any third party: 
    * **4.3.1** in order to enhance our service and the services we can offer you or where we have your consent to share the information;
    * **4.3.2** where we need to share the information to provide a product or service you have requested;
    * **4.3.3** where we need to send the information to persons or organisations who work on our behalf to provide a product or service to you but such persons or organisations may only use this information in order to provide such product or service and not for any other purpose;
    * **4.3.4** in the event that we sell or buy any business or assets, in which case we may disclose your personal data to the prospective seller or buyer of such business or assets; or
    * **4.3.5** where we are required to forward the information in order to comply with a regulatory or legal process.

## 5 Right of access to your information

  * **5.1** Should you wish to obtain a copy of the personal data we hold on you please write to Company Secretary, Persimmon plc, Persimmon House, Fulford, York YO19 4FE. Please note that a small fee will be payable.
  * **5.2** As soon as we are satisfied as to your identity we will send you within 30 days a copy of all the data we hold concerning you. 
  * **5.3** If it transpires that the information held is inaccurate, we will make the necessary amendments and confirm to you that these have been made.

## 6 How we protect your data

  * **6.1** The internet is not a secure medium, however we take we take all reasonable care to prevent any unauthorised access to your personal data.
  * **6.2** As a member, it is your responsibility to protect log-in details. You must treat these as confidential and must not share or disclose your log-in details to any other party.
  * **6.3** We will retain your information for a reasonable period or for as long as the law requires.

## 7 Use of Cookies

  * **7.1** When you access the Site and view developments and properties we record this activity and may place a unique "cookie" on your computer's hard disk. This enables us to show this information to you.
  * **7.2** We may work with third parties to research certain usage and activities on the Site on our behalf. No personal information about you is shared, however in the course of conducting this research these third parties may place a unique "cookie" on your computer's hard disk.
  * **7.3** A cookie is a small file which is sent to your browser and stored on your computer's hard disk and helps us understand and track your use of the Site and where we can improve the information and services provided.
  * **7.4** We use cookies solely to gather information on IP addresses, to analyse trends, administer the Site, track users' movements on the Site, gather broad demographic information for aggregate use and as set out in Clause 7.1. IP addresses are not linked to other personally identifiable information and will not be used to deliver targeted marketing messages. 
  * **7.5** For information about blocking the use of cookies, please refer to the instructions/help screen on your internet browser. Please note that you may not be able to use or access certain parts of the Site or online services if you block the use of cookies.

## 8 Links to Other Websites

  * **8.1** This Privacy Policy extends only to the Site and therefore does not extend to your use of, provision of data to, and collection of data on any website not connected to us to which you may link by using the hypertext links* within the Site. *Hypertext links are a means by which visitors can skip from one website to another or from one page to another within the same site. 

## 9 Changes

  * **9.1** We may edit or amend this Privacy Policy from time to time. If we make any substantial changes to the Privacy Policy, we will notify you by using a prominent notice on the home page of the Site.
  * **9.2** As a result of improvements we make to our services, amendments to laws or regulation or developments in the technology or processes we use, we may change the information we hold about you and/or the way in which or the purposes for which we process such information. If we make any substantial change in the way in which we use your personal information we will notify you by email.

## 10 Contact

Questions, comments and requests regarding this Privacy Policy are welcomed and should be addressed to Company Secretary, Persimmon plc, Persimmon House, Fulford, York YO19 4FE. You may also contact us by email at datachanges@persimmonhomes.com or by telephone on 01904 642119.

**March 2010**

### Personalising your new home

Whatever your style, from urban chic to classical English.

  * __ __ View styling options

### Our commitment

From the moment you reserve your new Persimmon home, we pledge to take care of you every step of the way.

  * __ __ Find out more
